keen.io 2017-05-15

# Privacy Policy | Keen IO

## Keen IO Analytics Service Privacy Policy

Note: this policy applies only to the Keen IO Analytics Service. It does not apply to the visitors of the Keen website.

## Keen IO Analytics Service Privacy Policy Abstract

We respect privacy and only share personal information when required to provide our services to our customers (e.g. payment processing). Personal information is not a monetization channel for us. We may, however, aggregate your user information that you provide to us or that we collect from third parties and use it to learn and share what we have learned about analytics, but all information will be deidentified. Cool? Again, this is just an abstract. The nitty gritty is listed below. If you think our abstract is inconsistent with our policy, let us know. We really want to be on the up and up.

## Keen IO Analytics Service Privacy Policy

Last updated: December 10, 2015

This Keen IO Analytics Services Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) explains how our practices regarding the information that is processed through our Analytics Service (“Service”).

### Consent

By submitting information through our Service, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy (or, if you are acting on behalf of your employer or other organization, you agree on behalf of such organization) and you expressly consent to the processing of such information according to this Privacy Policy.

In particular, you understand that information may be processed in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of information may be less stringent than the laws in your country, and you consent to such processing.

If you are submitting information pertaining to third parties for processing through our Service, you represent and warrant that you have adequately disclosed to such third parties that information about them would be processed by a service provider, and that these third parties did not object to the use of such services.

### Definitions

“Anonymous Data” means data that is not associated with or linked to Personal Data; Anonymous Data does not permit the identification of an individual.

“Customer” means a user of our Service. A Customer may use the Keen IO Analytics Service for his/her own purpose, or on behalf of his/her employer. Using the Keen IO tools available through the Service, the Customer can perform analyses of the use of websites in the custody or control of that Customer, or with respect to which the Customer is providing services to a third party.

“Data Subject” mean a user of a website for which the website operator wishes to obtain analysis of the usage patterns of the users of that website.

“Personal Data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, which is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.

### Overview of the Keen IO Service

The Keen IO Analytics Service allows businesses to obtain insights into event data by providing an API to collect, analyze, and visualize event data. When providing the Keen Analytics Service, Keen IO acts as a service provider to these businesses or their advisors, consultants or service providers; it does not have a direct relationship with the visitors of these websites.

As a service provider, Keen may have access to information that has been generated when an individual visits the website of a Keen Customer or a customer of a Keen Customer. Keen has no direct relationship with that individual. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain what the Keen Service does with these individuals’ data are uploaded on the Keen Platform.

Our Customers must inform the affected Data Subjects about the use of our Service and post a link to this Privacy Policy so that these Data Subjects are made aware of the Keen policies with respect to the handling and protection of Personal Data.

### What Information Keen IO Collects

We collect two categories of information:

##### Customer Information

  * We collect information concerning our Customers (the “Customer Information”). These individuals are using the Keen IO Analytics Service for their own purpose, or on behalf of their employer.
  * When you sign up for the Service we ask you to complete a registration form so that you can create an account. We also provide you with any API and a key, so that you can connect to the Service and upload your information.
  * When you register for an account, we collect certain profile information such as the registrant’s first and last name, and email address, and payment information.
  * If you send us feedback, request support, or otherwise interact with us with respect to the Service, we will collect any Personal Data in the email, message, or other communication to us.
  * We may combine Personal Data submitted by a user of our Service with information obtained from other sources.
  * Like most websites, Keen IO collects certain information provided by a user’s browser, such as Internet protocol address, browser type, operating system, and access time.

##### Data Subject Information

  * We collect information concerning Data Subjects. Our Service analyzes the usage patterns of these Data Subjects.
  * We collect all data that you upload on our platform as part of your use of the Service.
  * We do not control what data is uploaded. We request that you do not upload Personal Data.

### How Information is Collected

##### Customer Information

Customer information is collected through the use of forms (e.g. registration form) or from interaction with the Customer such as in connection with support request, in which case information is collected from electronic or phone communications.

We use cookies and navigational data, such as Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding a Customer’s use of the Service. A “cookie" is a small data file placed on your hard drive when you visit certain websites. Customers may disable cookies by adjusting the preferences settings of their browser. Instructions on how to adjust preferences can be found by consulting the “Help" feature of the browser. If you choose to disable cookies when using the Service, some areas of our website may not work properly.

##### Data Subject Information

Our Customers upload information from or about Data Subjects onto our Service.

Keen has no control over what information is uploaded. Keen is not responsible for any information that a Data Subject submits to our Customers, each of which may have its own policies regarding the collection and use of information. If you are a Data Subject, we recommend that you review the policies of our Customers through whom your information may be collected and uploaded on our Service.

### Do Not Track Notice

Some Internet browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features (“DNT”). DNT is a way for users to inform websites and services that they do not want certain information about their webpage visits collected over time and across websites or online services. When turned on, these features send a signal or preference (the “DNT Signal”) to the web sites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. We do not currently respond to the browser DNT signals on our Site or Services, or on third-party websites or online services where we provide advertisements, content, or are otherwise able to collect information.

##### Third Party Tracking

Our Web Site (not the Keen IO Service) may also send third party cookies to your browser, which may collect your online activities across different websites over time. The collection and use of information through these third party cookies are subject to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions of such third party websites. However, you can exercise choice regarding the collection of information by third parties about your online activities over time and across third party Web sites or online services for online interest based advertising purposes by going to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

### How Keen IO Uses Information

##### Customer Information

In general, we use your Personal Data to respond to requests from a customer or to aid us in serving better our Customer. We may use a Customer’s Personal Data, including information tracking the Customer’s use of our Service, to improve our website and Service.

We may use a Customer’s Personal Data to periodically send that Customer newsletters, administrative notices, updates regarding the Service and communications promoting the use of our Service. Customers may “opt-out” of such communications as set forth below.

##### Data Subject Information

Our Customers use our Service to analyze Data Subjects information to identify behaviors, build profiles, and more generally to better understand the needs and interests of the Data Subjects.

Keen has no control over the use of the Services by a Customer, and does not have access to the information collected by a Customer, except, as might be necessary to provide support services.

Keen does not use Data Subject information for its own purposes, other than in aggregated form, combined with other Data Subject information to create internal statistics for financial reporting and billing.

### How Keen IO Shares Your Information

Keen IO respects the privacy of its Customers and of all Data Subjects whose information might be stored on its platform in connection with the Service. We will not share the data you send us with any third-parties except in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

##### Third Parties

We will NOT use or share the data recorded in Keen IO in raw or aggregate form for any purposes other than internal metrics. Other than as provided in this Privacy Policy, we will not sell or distribute any data recorded in raw or aggregate form to any third parties or partners.

##### Service Providers

We may share Customer Personal Data with third party service providers, such as payment providers, to provide Customers with the Service. We may process or host Data Subject information through our service providers. These third party service providers are required not to use Personal Data other than to provide the services requested by us.

##### Business Transfers

If another company acquires Keen or Keen’s assets, that company will have access to all data saved on our platform, and will assume the rights and obligations described in this Privacy Policy.

##### Compliance with Laws and Third Party Requests

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Data (as described below), we may disclose Personal Data if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to facially valid court order, subpoenas, warrants or similar request for government or litigant access to data served on us; or (b) respond to and defend against legal claims, protect or defend our rights or property or those of our Customers.

### Your Options

When a Customer receives newsletters or promotional communications from us, the Customer may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive. These restrictions will not affect our distribution of administrative communications. We will continue to send our Customers administrative communications, such as notices of updates to this Privacy Policy.

### Your Rights

##### Right to Object to New Uses of Your Data

If at any time you wish to disclose, or use Customer Personal Data in a way or for a purpose that is materially different from that which is described in this Privacy Policy, we will give the Customer the opportunity to choose whether Personal Data that identifies that Customer may be used for a purpose other than the purposes that are set forth in this Privacy Policy.

##### Right to Know about Third Party Marketing

We do not share any Personal Data with any third party for the direct marketing purposes of these third parties.

##### Right to Access and Correct Personal Data

Customers may change their Personal Data by editing their profile or by sending us an e-mail. Other than Customer Personal Data, we do not collect or store any data that may be linked to an individual, and we do not attempt to link Data Subject data to a specific individual.

### Links to Third Party Site

Our provision of a link to any other website or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. When you click on such a link, you will leave our site and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Data or Anonymous Data from you. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on links to such outside websites.

### Security

Keen IO is committed to protecting the security of all information in our custody. We use a variety of reasonable security technologies and procedures to help protect all information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, including limiting access to the data within Keen IO. Despite these measures, Keen IO cannot fully eliminate security risks and mistakes may happen that could cause the information of a Data Subject to be inadvertently disclosed.

### International Transfer

Customer data and Data Subject data may be transferred, stored, maintained, and processed in the United States or in other countries where we have facilities or where we have engaged a service provider. This storage, maintenance, or processing will be performed under privacy and security laws and standards that may not be as protective as those in the jurisdiction where the data was originally collected. We require our service providers to commit in writing to process our data in a manner consistent with our directives.

### Safe Harbor

Keen adheres to the Safe Harbor Agreement concerning the transfer of Personal Data from the European Economic Area and Switzerland, and follows the Safe Harbor Principles published by the US Department of Commerce (“Principles”) with respect to such Data. Our certification can be found at <https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx>.

**If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Statement and the Principles, the Principles shall govern.**

This published Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, completely implemented, accessible and conforms to the Safe Harbor Principles. In addition, we provide appropriate employee training (and discipline) and have internal procedures for periodically conducting objective reviews of our compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles. A statement verifying the self-assessment is signed by a corporate officer or other authorized representative of the organization annually.

For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce website at <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

### Disputes

If you have any concerns or claims with respect to our Privacy Policy, please contact us as indicated in the “Contact Us” below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding our use and disclosure of the Customer Data and Data Subject Data described in this Privacy Policy.

If the complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through our internal process, and Keen does not adequately respond to your question, please contact the nearest JAMS location for resolution of any such complaint or dispute. See <http://www.jamsadr.com/locations/> for a list of JAMS locations and contact information.

### Changes to this Policy

If we make any substantial changes in the way we use Personal Data, we will prominently post notice of the changes on our website. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our website.

Changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of Customer’s Personal Data that we collected before our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your Personal Data, you must notify us before the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your Customer account with us. Continued use of our website or Service, following notice of such changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

We have no control over the type of data or information that Customers upload on our Service. We you are a Data Subject, and you wish to prevent the uploading and analysis of your information through our Service, you must contact the entity that has uploaded this information on our Service.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions or feedback regarding this Privacy Policy, please let us know. Please contact us at [privacy@keen.io](mailto:privacy@keen.io).
